Finding Aid for the Cole Family Papers LSC.0217
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Miscellaneous Papers and Objects, 1833-1943
  - Photographs
    - Photographs, Printed Material, Postcards, Ephemera. (Box 75)
- Correspondence and Papers of Olive Howard Waring,, [and Howard S. Waring], 1898-1941; (Approximately 500 pieces)
  - Correspondence and Writings of Olive H. Waring, 1898-1941
    - Olive H. Waring to various persons, 1898-1938; 26 pieces. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Letters written from Los Angeles and other places concerning family matters, University of Southern California, genealogy of the Cole family.
    - Various persons to Olive H. Waring, 1919-1941; 84 pieces. (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Letters concerning the University of California, University of Southern California, Alaska, Cole family genealogy, 5 letters from Catherine C. Phillips concerning her biography of Cornelius Cole.
    - Writings of Olive H. Waring, 1920-1925; 1 journal. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Master's thesis; copy and fragments. Short stories and plays; typescript drafts. 9 pieces. Bound record book containing transcriptions by Olive H. Waring of comments by Cornelius Cole on various subjects, 1920. The transcriptions concern Lyman Trumbull, James A. Garfield, Andrew Johnson, Ulysses S. Grant, Nathaniel Banks, Richard Yates, Benjamin Wade, William Smith, Governor of Virginia, William Parson Brownlow, Henry S. Foote, Francis D., Montgomery, and Francis P. Blair Jr., negro troops, Hiram Johnson, Salmon P. Chase, Alaska Purchase, Stoeckl, Cassius M. Clay, William M. Gwin, William H. Seward, early California newspapers, Leland Stanford, Collis P. Huntington, A.A. Sargent, Abraham Lincoln.
    - Olive Waring to Lucretia (Cole) Waring, 48 pieces. (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Mostly n.d. letters and fragments written when Olive was a young girl.
    - Olive Waring to various relatives. (Box 69, Folder 2)
      n.d. letters to Olive and Cornelius Cole.
    - Howard Waring to Olive Waring., 5 pieces. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Letters written at sea during the 1890s.
    - Relatives to Olive Waring., 1903-1909; 30 pieces. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Letters from cousin Marge, Cornelius and Olive Cole.
    - Various persons to Olive Waring., 1911-1936; 16 pieces. (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Letters concerning Cole papers and Lincoln materials.
    - Papers of Olive Waring., 10 pieces. (Box 69, Folder 6)
      School diplomas and related materials.
  - Miscellaneous papers of Olive H. Waring, 1899-1940
    - Manuscript notes by Olive H. Waring on historical and literary subjects., 90 pieces. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Papers and drafts concerning the school projects and activities of Olive H. Waring., 98 pieces. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous papers and newspaper clippings, 135 pieces. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Concerning Olive Cole, Cornelius Cole, George T. Cole, Lucretia Cole Waring, cards signed by Senator John Jones, programs, mementos of Olive H. Waring, card concerning the inauguration of McKinley and Roosevelt.
  - Objects and memorabilia of Olive H. Waring., 1898-1931; 18 pieces. (Box 43)
    10 photographs of Lucretia Cole, Cornelius Cole, Olive Cole, Olive H. Waring; 2 books from the library of Cornelius Cole.
  - Correspondence and Papers of Howard S. Waring
    - Howard S. Waring to Flora Waring Herrick., 1869-1878; 16 pieces. (Box 70, Folder 1)
      Letters written from Annapolis, at sea, China. Also photograph.
    - Howard S. Waring to his mother, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 2)
      Letter written from New London.
    - Various persons to Howard S. Waring., 1872-1883; 2 pieces. (Box 70, Folder 3)
      Letters concerning sailing orders and promotion.
    - Papers of Howard S. Waring., 1867-1885; 9 pieces. (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Commissions from Midshipman to Lieutenant U.S. Navy, signed and sealed.
    - Miscellaneous papers concerning Howard S. Waring. (Box 70, Folder 5)
      Includes obituary of Waring, notes on the cruise of the U.S.S. Rodgers.
  - Bound Volumes Concerning Howard S. Waring
    - Photo Albums. (Box 76)
      2 albums of photographs of Alaska and cruises in northern waters, scrapbooks concerning Russia, Alaska, Canada, and cruises of exploration by U.S. Navy ships, including the U.S.S. Rodgers. 7 vol. oversize. Included are photos of Waring and friends, not bound in volumes.
    - Scrapbooks. (Box 77)
- Papers of Cole Family Law Partnerships, 1887-1916
  - Correspondence and Papers of Cole Family Law Partnerships, 1896-1916
    - Letters from Cole family law partnerships, 1896-1916; 6 pieces. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      The partnerships concerned are those of Cole and Cole, and Cole and Brown.
    - Letters to Cole family law partnerships., 1889-1916; 12 pieces. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Letters concerning cases on the subjects of patents, lands, property, and claims.
    - Manuscript legal notes concerning patents., n.d; 152 leaves. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      In holograph of Cornelius or Willoughby Cole.
    - Printed case summaries and other documents., 10 pieces. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Papers and Documents Relating to Cases Handled By Cole Family Law Partnerships, 1887-1916
    - Papers and documents relating to cases., 1887-1889; 30 pieces. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Case subjects include reclamation of lands in California, Temple Street [Los Angeles] Cable Company.
    - Papers and documents relating to cases., 1890-1892; 70 pieces. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Case subjects include continuation of Temple street and other Los Angeles highway cases related to it, real estate and private claims.
    - Papers and documents relating to cases., 1893-1916; 15 pieces. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Case subjects include personal suits and inheritances, patents.
  - Case Record Books of Cole Family Law Partnerships, 1894-1916
    - vol.1: Cases., 1894-1902 (Box 46)
    - vol.2: Cases., 1902-1905 (Box 46)
    - vol.3: Cases., 1905-1912 (Box 46)
    - vol.4: Cases., 1912-1916 (Box 46)